(
"ai_sub_version": "3.6.0",
"generated_at": "2026-10-06T23:00:46.772964",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": false,
"max_retries_exceeded": true,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.7-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"service_tier": null,
"service_tier_subtitles": null,
"service_tier_lyrics": null,
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
せーの
Ready, go!
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that won't do,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
no, that's not enough, look!
心は進化するよ
My heart will keep evolving,
もっと もっと
more and more!
言葉にすれば消えちゃう関係なら
If our relationship would just disappear once put into words,
言葉を消せばいいやって思ってた 恐れてた
I thought I should just erase the words—I was scared.
だけどあれ？ なんか違うかも
Wait, huh? Maybe something's different...
千里の道も一歩から！
Even a journey of a thousand miles begins with a single step!
石のように固い そんな意志で
With a determination as solid as stone,
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ？
even dust piled up makes an ideal maiden?
『し』抜きで いや 死ぬ気で！
Without "shi"—no, with all my might!
ふわふわり ふわふわる
Fluffy, floating, drifting, wandering...
あなたが名前を呼ぶ
When you call my name,
それだけで宙へ浮かぶ
just that makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり
Drifting, wandering, fluffy, floating...
あなたが笑っている
When you're smiling,
それだけで笑顔になる
just that brings a smile to my face.
神様 ありがとう
Dear God, thank you so much!
運命の悪戯でも
Even if it's just a prank of fate,
めぐり逢えたことが
being able to meet you
しあわせなの
makes me so happy.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ
But that won't do,
もう そんなんじゃ ほら
no, that's not enough, look!
心は進化するよ
My heart will keep evolving,
もっと もっと
more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ やだ
Yeah, I don't want it like that!
ねえ そんなんじゃ まだ
Hey, that's not quite enough yet!
私の中のあなたほど あなたの中の私の存在は
My presence within you isn't nearly as big...
まだまだ大きくないことも 分かってるけれど
...as your presence is within me, I know, but still...
今この同じ瞬間 共有してる時間
Right now in this very moment, this time that we share...
塵も積もればやまとなでしこ？ 略して ちりつもやまとなでこ！
"Dust piled up makes a Yamato Nadeshiko"? In short, "Chiritsumo Yamato Nadeko"!
くらくらり くらくらる あなたを見上げたら
Getting so dizzy, spinning around... Just looking up at you,
それだけで 眩しすぎて
is dazzling enough on its own.
くらくらる くらくらり あなたを想っている
Spinning around, getting so dizzy... Just thinking of you,
それだけで 溶けてしまう
is enough to make me melt away.
神様 ありがとう
God, thank you so much,
運命の悪戯でも
even if it's just a trick of fate...
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
being able to meet you brings me so much happiness.
コ・イ・ス・ル・キ・モ・チ・ワ・フ・ク・ザ・ツ・サ・ー・キ・ュ・レ・ー・シ・ョ・ン
Falling-in-love-feelings-are-a-complex-circulation!
コ・イ・ス・ル・オ・ト・メ・ワ・フ・ク・ザ・ツ・サ・ー・キ・ュ・レ・ー・シ・ョ・ン
A-maiden-falling-in-love-is-a-complex-circulation!
ふわふわり ふわふわる あなたが名前を呼ぶ
Floating, drifting gently... When you call my name,
それだけで 宙へ浮かぶ
that alone makes me float into the air.
ふわふわる ふわふわり あなたが笑っている
Drifting gently, floating away... Seeing you smile,
それだけで 笑顔になる
that alone brings a smile to my face.
神様 ありがとう
God, thank you so much,
運命の悪戯でも
even if it's just a trick of fate...
めぐり逢えたことが しあわせなの
being able to meet you brings me so much happiness.
でも そんなんじゃ だめ もう そんなんじゃ ほら
But that won't do; no, not like that, look!
心は進化するよ もっと もっと
My heart will keep evolving more and more!
そう そんなんじゃ やだ ねえ そんなんじゃ まだ
Yeah, I don't want it like that; hey, not like that yet!
私のこと 見ててね ずっと ずっと
Keep your eyes on me forever and ever!
「聞こえますか…？」激情奏でる ミュージック
"Can you hear it...?" The music playing pure passion...
天に解き放て
Unleash it to the heavens!
「聴こえますか…？」イノチ始まる脈動
"Can you hear it...?" The pulse where life begins...
愛を突き上げて
Thrust up your love!
遥か (彼方) 星が (音楽となった…彼の日)
Far, far away, on that day the stars became music...
風が (髪を) 攫う (瞬間)
The moment the wind swept through our hair,
君と僕はコドウを詩にした
you and I turned our heartbeats into song.
そして (夢は) (開くよ)
And then, our dreams will open up,
見た事ない世界の果てへ…
to the ends of an unseen world...
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない ヒカリで歴史を創ろう
Let's create history with a light unknown even to God!
逆光のシャワー 未来照らす
A shower of backlighting illuminating the future...
一緒に飛ばないか
Won't you fly with me?
Just feeling 涙で濡れた羽根 重くて羽撃けない日は
Just feeling, on days your wings are wet and too heavy with tears to flap...
Wish その右手に添えよう
Wish, I will place beside your right hand...
僕のチカラも
my power too!
二人で行けば 翼になれる
If we go together, we can become wings!
Singing heart
いつの日にか解る時が来るから
Because the time will surely come when you understand...
ずっと…忘れない
Never... forget.
その時には心のあるがままに
At that time, just as your heart desires...
笑顔…忘れない
Don't forget... to smile.
きっと (僕と) 君は (君は)
Surely, you and I...
一羽の鳥のように
...like a single bird,
遠い (過去も) 手と手繋ぎ
holding hands even in the distant past,
大空を強く翔けていたんだ
soared strongly across the vast sky.
そして (生きる) 今を
And living in the present,
見た事ない明日の先へ
we'll head beyond an unseen tomorrow!
Yes, just believe
1000年後の今日も 生まれ変わって歌いたい
A thousand years from now, I want to be reborn and sing today!
暖かいよ この温もり
It's so warm, this warmth...
絶対離さない
I'll never let it go!
Just feeling
運命なんてない 物語は自分にある
There's no such thing as destiny; the story belongs to us!
Jump
逃げ出したくなったら 宇宙を見上げよう
If you ever want to run away, look up at the cosmos!
勇気こそが輝くんだよ
Courage is what truly shines!
Singing star
遥か (彼方) 星が (音楽となった…) あの日
That day in the far distance when the stars became music...
たぶん (僕は) 君と (出会い)
Perhaps I met you,
神話の一つのように紡いだ
and we spun together like a myth.
何も (怖く) ないよ
There's nothing to fear,
見た事ない世界の果てへ…
towards the ends of an unseen world...
Yes, just believe
神様も知らない 二人で歴史を創ろう
Unknown even to God, let's create our own history together!
逆光のシャワー 未来照らす 一緒に飛ばないか
A shower of backlight illuminates the future—won't you fly with me?
Just feeling
涙で濡れた羽 重くて羽撃けない日は
On days when wings soaked in tears are too heavy to flap,
Wish
旋律は溶け合って シンフォニーへと
melodies melt together into a symphony.
二人でなら 翼になれる
If we're together, we can become wings!
Singing heart
もっと高く 太陽よりも高く
Higher and higher, higher than the sun!
UNHAPPY? 悩める人の子よ
Unhappy? O troubled child of man,
UNLUCKY? 人成らざる者も
Unlucky? Even non-human beings,
BE HAPPY! 弛まず目指せよ
Be happy! Strive for it tirelessly!
生きているんだし 目を逸らした過去も
Since you're alive, both the past you looked away from
退屈な未来も
and the boring future—
カウンセリング やれやれ 古今東西 ピースピース
counseling them—good grief! Everywhere and always, peace peace!
UNHAPPY? UNLUCKY? BE HAPPY!
UNDEAD
ねえ ねえ ねえ ねえ 何だかどうして 戦ってるようなそんな気がするの
Hey, hey, hey, hey, why do I feel like I'm fighting something?
触れられない 触れたくもない
Can't touch, don't want to touch.
過去の自分 自分 自分 自分とも もうとっくに死んでる 透明な亡霊と対決
Confronting my past self—an invisible ghost already long dead.
幼気で痛い 記憶の奥
Deep in naive, painful memories.
残念 もう居ないのに あれ？ そっちが良い？ アイロニーね
Too bad, they're not here anymore. Huh? You prefer that? How ironic.
透かされているのは 現在の自分？
Is the one being seen through my current self?
ナンセンス
Nonsense.
消えないレッテル (Yes!)
An indelible label (Yes!)
要はコンプレックス
In short, a complex.
取り憑かれてるみたい 巻き付いたまま まだ離れの
Like being possessed, wrapped tight, still drifting apart,
在りし日の自分
the self from days gone by.
UNDEAD
死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
Not dead yet—a continuous chain of you and you.
生きていることとは 変わり続けることだ
To live means to keep changing!
不幸に甘んじて 満足するなよ
Don't settle for misfortune and be satisfied!
幸せになろうと しないなんて 卑怯だ
Refusing to try to be happy is sheer cowardice!
この世 此の世は 奇怪 奇怪 ファンタジー
This world, this life is a bizarre, eerie fantasy.
次は鬼が出るか 蛇が出るか
Will a demon appear next, or a snake?
出逢って 逢って やっと始まる物語
Meeting and crossing paths, our story finally begins.
さあ人か 化物か 閑話休題 ピースピース
Now, are you human or a monster? Anyway, peace peace!
Past and Future, can't change the Past
Past and Future, run for the Future
カットイン
Cut in!
何だかどうして 未来になんぞ 何の希望もない ような気がして
Somehow, for some reason, I feel like there's no hope for the future.
もう随分生きてる 既視感とテンプレで食傷
Having lived this long, I'm sick of déjà vu and cliches.
素敵な出来事の気配もない 残念
No sign of anything wonderful happening. Too bad!
積んだ経験の因果 形骸化された神話と退屈な進化
The cause and effect of accumulated experience, a hollowed myth and tedious evolution.
要は刺激が欲しいんだ (飽きちゃった 慣れちゃった)
Basically, I want excitement ("I'm bored, I'm used to it")
なんて 整ってくガイダンス 増えるコンプライアンス
And yet, guidance gets tidied up, compliance increases,
塞がれていくみたい 吸い尽くして
feeling like everything is blocked up—drain it dry!
あれも これも どれも 吸い尽くして
Sucking everything dry, this, that, and that too,
同じ味がする
they all taste the same.
UNDEAD 死んじゃない お前とお前の連鎖
UNDEAD, you're not dead; this chain of you and you,
何時の世も過去も未来も 現在にあるんだ
across any era, past and future, exists in the present!
生きていることを 愚直に果たせよ
Fulfill the act of living with pure honesty,
目指せ ハッピーエンド
and aim for a happy ending!
UNDEAD 死んじゃない お前に言っているんだ
UNDEAD, you're not dead—I'm telling you!
幸せを諦めてしまうな 人で在れ
Don't give up on happiness; remain human!
ただ苦しみに慣れて 耐えているだけじゃ
Just getting used to pain and enduring it
死んでるも同然 屍の UNDEAD
is as good as being dead, a corpse of the UNDEAD!
Unhappy? 悩める人の子よ Unlucky? 人ならざる者も
Unhappy? Troubled child of man. Unlucky? You inhuman beings too,
Be happy 絶えず目指せよ 生きているんだろ
Be happy, strive for it constantly—you're alive, aren't you?!
不幸に浸るも 幸せになるのも そう全部全部お前だ
Wallowing in misery or finding happiness—it's all up to you!
古今東西 一切合切 森羅万象 ピースピース
Across all time and space, everything and all creation, peace, peace!
Past and Future can't change the Past
Past and Future run for the Future
人の在る所に 何時も濁り言
Wherever people dwell, murky rumors always gather.
生き抜けこの 化け物ばかりの物語
Survive this story full of monsters!
Stop, listen, rewind
Come a little closer
Listen to the silence beating hard
Wherever you go
Fast forward in time
Time's moving in deeper
All deeper and deeper into you
There is no way out
It must have been the time when I lost my way
Through the chaos of time it was stormy
Spinning out of it all
You left me in life of confusion
You left me in a life of confusion
Take a time to remember when I met you
Take time to remember when I met you
See the truth beneath all the lies and hate
Nothing wrong being scared
Nothing's wrong with being scared
We're all the same tomorrow
Hear what I'm saying
Rewind our vision
I want to hold you
Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back and today
Just explore
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
Stop my tears rewind
Overlapping blue shadows
Touching in the darkness far away
Wishing it was real
Stay with me tonight
I don't want this sadness
Sadness overflowing in my mind
I wanna hold on
Hear what I'm saying
Rewind your vision
I want your heartbeat
I want you wanting me
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
I can't remember days without you
Take my hand
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
Stay with me tonight
Rewind our vision
I want to hold you
Please take a moment now
Let me into your heart
Rewind your vision
Don't let it hold you back and today
Just explore
We can fall in love
You know the truth is there
Let me know why
Between us love
いつも通りのある日のこと
On an ordinary day, just like any other,
君は突然立ち上がり言った
you suddenly stood up and said,
「今夜星を見に行こう」
"Let's go look at the stars tonight."
「たまには良いこと言うんだね」なんて
"You actually have a good idea for once,"
みんなして言って笑った
we all said and laughed,
明かりもない道を
and along the pitch-black path,
バカみたいにはしゃいで歩いた
we walked and goofed around like idiots,
抱え込んだ孤独や不安に
so that we wouldn't be crushed
押しつぶされないように
by the loneliness and anxiety we held inside.
真っ暗な世界から見上げた
Looking up from this pitch-dark world,
夜空は星が降るようで
the night sky looked as if stars were raining down.
いつからだろう 君のことを
When did I start...
追いかける私がいた
...chasing after you?
どうかお願い 驚かないで
Please, I beg you, don't be surprised,
聞いてよ
and just listen...
私のこの思いを
...to these feelings of mine.
あれがデネブ、アルタイル、ベガ
That's Deneb, Altair, Vega.
君は指さす夏の大三角
You point out the Summer Triangle.
覚えて空を見る
Remembering that, I look at the sky.
やっと見つけた織姫様
I finally found Vega, the Weaver Princess,
だけどどこだろう彦星様
but where could Altair, the Cowherd, be?
これじゃひとりぼっち
Like this, she's all alone.
楽しげな ひとつ隣の君
Next to me, you look so happy,
私は 何も言えなくて
and I couldn't say a single word.
本当はずっと 君のことを
Truth is, deep down in my heart,
どこかでわかっていた
I had always known about you.
見つかったって 届きはしない
Even if I find them, they're out of reach.
だめだよ 泣かないで
No, don't cry.
そう言い聞かせた
That's what I told myself.
強がる私は臆病で
Putting on a brave face, I was a coward,
興味がないようなふりをしてた
pretending like I didn't care at all.
だけど
And yet...
胸を刺す痛みは増してく
...the piercing pain in my chest only grows.
ああそうか 好きになるって
Ah, I see, falling in love...
こういう事なんだね
...means feeling like this.
「どうしたい？言ってごらん」
"What do you want to do? Go on, tell me."
心の声がする
A voice inside my heart speaks.
君の隣がいい
I want to be right by your side.
真実は残酷だ
But the truth is cruel.
言えなかった　言えなかった
I couldn't say it, I couldn't say it.
二度と戻れない
We can never return to it again.
あの夏の日　きらめく星
That summer day, those twinkling stars...
今でも思い出せるよ
Even now, I can still remember them all.
笑った顔も　怒った顔も
Your smiling face, your angry face...
大好きでした
I loved every bit of it.
おかしいよね　分かってたのに
Funny, isn't it? Even though I already knew...
君の知らない　私だけの秘密
It's a secret just for me, one you'll never know.
夜を越えて　遠い思い出の
Reaching beyond the night, in a distant memory,
君が指をさす
you point up towards the sky,
無邪気な声で
with that innocent voice of yours.
I know this will not remain forever
However it's beautiful
Your eyes, hands and your warm smile, they're my treasure
It's hard to forget
I wish there was a solution, don't spend your time in confusion
I'll turn back now and spread
My broken wings, still strong enough to cross the ocean with
My broken wings, how far should I go drifting in the wind?
Higher and higher in the light
My broken wings, still strong enough to cross the ocean with
My broken wings, how far should I go drifting in the wind?
Across the sky, just keep on flying
計測のできない痛みと　計測のできない時間の流れが　すべてを埋めてしまおうとしても
Even if immeasurable pain and the unmeasurable flow of time try to bury everything away,
それでも私には感じられる
even so, I can still feel it.
空から落ちてくるのは　空から落ちてくるのは　雨ではなくて…
What falls from the sky... what falls from the sky isn't rain, but...
Did I ever chain you down to my heart?
'Cause I was afraid of you?
No, I couldn't hold any longer, love is not a toy
Let go of me now
The time we spent is perpetual, our future is not real
So I'll leap into the air
My broken wings, still strong enough to cross the ocean with
My broken wings...
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Higher and higher in the light
still strong enough to cross the ocean with
my broken wings
How far should I go drifting in the wind
Across the sky, just keep on flying
空から落ちてくるのは
What falls from the sky...
あれは雨ではなくて…
That is not rain, but...
認めてた臆病な過去
I had accepted my cowardly past
わからないままに
without ever really understanding,
怖がってた後ろの自分が
and the self behind me, full of fear,
現実を今に映す
now reflects reality onto the present.
いくつもの空を描いた
I painted so many skies;
ここはきっと儚い心 見出して
surely here, my fragile heart is found.
夢で高く跳んだ体は
My body, soaring high in a dream,
どんな不安纏っても振り払っていく
shakes off whatever anxiety clings to it.
眠る小さな想い拡がりだして
My dormant little feelings begin to spread,
気付く弱い私 君がいれば
and I realize I'm weak—yet if you're here,
暗い世界強くいれた
I can stay strong in this dark world.
長い夢見る心はそう永遠で
Yes, this heart that dreams a long dream is eternal.
I wanna always be with you
I'll give you everything I have
探してた導く光
The guiding light I've been searching for,
触れればすべて
if I touch it, everything...
思い出して
Remember,
かけがえのない大切な今をくれる
it gives us this irreplaceable, precious present moment.
目を閉じ世界を知った
Closing my eyes, I came to know the world.
それはいつも温かいのに痛くて
Though it was always warm, it brought pain.
繋ぐ確かな願い重なり合って
Our certain wishes overlapping as they connect,
見える迷いは動き始めた
the visible hesitation has begun to move.
君を守りたくて
Wanting to protect you,
背負う傷は
the wounds I carry...
深い眠りの中漂った
...drifted in a deep sleep.
変わらない約束だった
It was an unchanging promise,
二人信じた絆はそう鮮明に
and the bond we both believed in remains so vivid.
声が届くまで
Until my voice reaches you,
名前を呼んで
call out my name.
出会えた奇跡感じたいもっと
I want to feel the miracle of meeting you even more.
夢で高く跳んだ体は
My body, soaring high in a dream,
どんな不安纏っても振り払っていく
shakes off whatever anxiety clings to it.
眠る小さな想い拡がりだして
My dormant little feelings begin to spread,
気付く弱い私 君がいれば
and I realize I'm weak—yet if you're here,
暗い世界強くいれた
I can stay strong in this dark world.
長い夢見る心はそう永遠で
Yes, this heart that dreams a long dream is eternal.
I wanna always be with you
I wanna hold you tight right now
I swear I will wipe your tear
I swear I will wipe your tears
I give you everything I have
I'll give you everything I have
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world,
そういう扱い心得てよね
make sure you know how to treat me like one!
よね
Got that?
その一 いつもと違う髪型に気がつくこと
Rule one: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual!
その二 ちゃんと靴までみること いいね？
Rule two: Make sure to look all the way down to my shoes, got it?
その三 わたしの一言には3つの言葉で返事すること
Rule three: Answer with three words to anything I say!
わかったら右手が留守なのを
If you understand, my right hand is feeling lonely,
なんとかして！
so do something about it!
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm asking for anything unreasonable.
キミに心から思ってほしいの
I just want you to truly think
かわいいって
that I'm cute.
ほしいの かわいいって
I want you to think I'm cute,
かわいいって
that I'm cute,
that I'm cute.
ほしいの かわいい
I want to be cute.
世界で一番おひめさま
The number one princess in the world,
気がついて ねえねえ
pay attention to me, hey, hey!
待たせるなんて論外よ
Making me wait is totally out of the question!
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もう なんだか あまいものが食べたい！
Jeez, now I feel like eating something sweet!
今すぐに よ
Right this instant!
欠点？ かわいいの間違いでしょ
Flaws? You must be mistaken for cuteness.
文句は許しませんの
Complaining will not be tolerated!
あのね？ 私の話 ちゃんと聞いてる？ ちょっと…
Hey, are you actually listening to me? Wait a second...
あ、それとね？ 白いおうまさん 決まってるでしょ？ 迎えに来て
Ah, also? A white horse, obviously, right? Come pick me up on one!
わかったら かしずいて 手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand, bow down, take my hand, and call me "Princess"!
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm asking for anything unreasonable.
でもね
But you know...
少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
it's okay to scold me a little bit, you know?
世界で わたしだけの王子さま
The prince meant only for me in the whole world,
気がついて ほらほら
take notice, look, look!
おててが空いてます
My hands are empty!
無口で無愛想な王子さま
A silent and unsociable prince...
もう どうして！ 気がついてよ早く
Oh, why?! Hurry up and realize it already!
ぜったいキミは分かってない！
You definitely don't get it at all!
分かってないわ…
You don't get it at all...
Yeah
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
A shortcake topped with strawberries,
こだわり卵のとろけるプリン
melt-in-your-mouth pudding made with special eggs...
みな みな 我慢します…
I'll hold back on all of them...
わがままな子だと思わないで
So don't think of me as a selfish girl!
私だってやればできるもん
I can do it if I try!
あとで後悔するわよ
You're going to regret this later!
当然です！ だって私は
Of course! Because I am...
世界で一番おひめさま
the number one princess in the world!
ちゃんと見ててよね どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Keep your eyes on me, or I might wander off, okay?
ふいに抱きしめられた 急に そんな え？
Suddenly, you hugged me out of nowhere... What?
「轢かれる 危ないよ」そう言ってそっぽ向くキミ
"You'll get run over, look out," you say, looking away.
…こっちのが危ないわよ
...You're the one who's dangerous here!
はい！ ということで、みなさーん！
All right! With that said, hello everyone!
獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026 STRAY AND STAYにお越しくださりありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to Shishiro Botan Birthday Festival 2026 STRAY AND STAY!
ということで、ららいおん獅白ぼたんでーす。
And so, I'm Lalion, Shishiro Botan!
配信のハッシュタグ、改めて右上… 右上…
Once again, the stream hashtag is in the top right... top right...
どっちだ？ もうどっちか！よろしくお願いします。こっちです。
Which way is it? Well, one of the sides! It's over here.
獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026、たくさん呟いてください。
Please tweet a lot with #獅白ぼたん生誕祭2026!
私も、えー、チェックしますんで、よろしくお願いします！
I'll be checking them out too, so please post away!
ということで
And with that...
早速なんですけど、次のパートの…ま、次…の次かな？ちょっと色々あるんですけど
Moving right along, for the next part... or maybe next-next? There's various things coming up,
ま、次のパートのゲストをお呼びして、一緒にちょっとMCやっていきたいと思います！
but I'd like to invite the guests for the next part and do some MC-ing together!
ということで、来いよ！いつものメンバーたちよ！
So with that, come on out! The usual members!
イエーイ！
Yay--!
来たぜ！いつもの！
We're here! The usuals!
おめでとうございます！おめでとうございますー！
Happy birthday! Congratulations!
いつものメンバーたちが、ということで。じゃ、ちょっと改めて自己紹介してもらおうかな？じゃ、もう…はい、ねねちから。
The usual members are here! So let's have you guys introduce yourselves once again. First up, Nenechi.
はい！ねぽらぼのね、桃鈴ねねです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! I'm the 'Ne' in Nepolabo, Momosuzu Nene! Pleased to be here!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい、次！ねぽらぼの「ぽ」、尾丸ポルカです！よろしくお願いしまーす！
All right, next! The 'Po' of Nepolabo, Omaru Polka here! Nice to meet you all!
イエーイ！よろしくお願いします！
Yay! Welcome!
はい、次。「ら」！
Next, 'La'!
はい！ねぽらぼの「ら」、ホロライブ5期生、顔が肝臓、雪花ラミィです！よろしくお願いします！
Yes! The 'La' of Nepolabo, Hololive 5th gen, my face is a liver, Yukihana Lamy! Nice to meet you!
イエーイ！
Yay!
ということで。お馴染みの面子揃いました。
And with that, the familiar lineup is here.
生誕祭始まっちゃいましたけど、これ、ど、どうですか？
The birthday fest has started, but how is it so far?
お馴染みの顔を見ると安心するね！
Seeing familiar faces really puts me at ease!
良かった良かった！
Glad to hear that!
いや、もう来年もよろしくお願いします！
Well, look forward to next year as well!
気が早いわ！
You're jumping the gun!
「良いお年を」みたいな。ステージめちゃかっこいい！
Like saying "Have a great new year" already! The stage is so cool!
ステージかっこいい！ネオンがすごい！ちょっとネオン、ピカピカしてますけど。
The neon is amazing! It is pretty flashy with all the neon.
ピカピカ、好きだよなー！好きだね！
You love flashy things, don't you! I sure do!
やっぱ好きなの結構、めっちゃ食べる方だからさ、こういうのもめっちゃ使っちゃうよね！
When I like something, I'm the type to consume a ton of it, so I ended up using a whole lot of this too!
あーね！要素いっぱいだね！
Ah, right! Packed with elements!
近未来的な！そうなんすよ。
Very futuristic! Exactly.
ちなみにコンセプトとかあるんですか？
By the way, is there a specific concept?
今回結構アニメの曲とかもたくさん歌わせてもらってたんで、
Since I've been singing a lot of anime songs today,
プラスなんか私の好きなそのEDMというか、サイバー感が好きなんで、ちょっと合体した感じかな？
plus I love things like EDM and the cyber vibe, it's kind of a fusion of those!
どパってる？どパってる感じ？
Is it "dopat"-ing? Having that dopamine rush feel?
どパってる感じ！どパってるか！
It's dopat-ing! Dopat-ing, huh!
どパってる感じ！どパってっかー！
A dopat-ing feel! Getting that dopamine hit!
はい、ということでね。ここまでをまあ色々振り返ってみようかなとも思ったんですけど、
Yes! So, I was thinking we could look back on everything so far, but...
どうしようかな。なんか私、今日1曲目にさ、『恋愛サーキュレーション』を歌ったんですよ。
what should we do? Today for my first song, I actually sang "Renai Circulation".
おーー！可愛かった！
Ooh! That was so cute!
可愛かったか？ちょっと久々に、なんか可愛いの見せちゃったなーと思って！
Was it cute? I thought to myself, "Man, it's been a while since I showed something cute!"
てれてれ。ぶりっ子が入ってた？可愛いでしょ？
Bashful. Were you acting cutesy? Wasn't it cute?
可愛い！獅子ろんはいつでも可愛い！出てた、4歳が出てたよ！
Cute! Shishiron is always cute! It came out, your 4-year-old self came out!
今回で何歳になった？
How old did you turn this time?
今回、でも4歳から次の『Flügel』、そらちゃんと歌った時にもう20歳ぐらいになったから。
Well, I went from 4 years old to around 20 years old when I sang "Flügel" with Sora-chan.
飛んだー！かっこよく飛んだから！
You leaped! You leaped gracefully!
色々ちょっとMCがてら紹介したいことがあって、
There are a few things I'd like to announce during this MC break,
ちょっとお手伝いしていただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
and I'd love it if you could help me out.
じゃ、ちょっと告知…はい、告知させていただきたいと思います！
Then let's... yes, let's move on to the announcements!
まずは獅白ぼたん生誕…生誕記念2026のグッズの販売告知となります！
First up is the sales announcement for the Shishiro Botan Birthday Celebration 2026 merch!
わー！パチパチ！
Yay--!
こちら、じゃん！えーかわいい！
Here it is, tada! Whoa, so pretty!
はい、イラストはママ、トマリ先生に描いていただきました。ありがとうございます！
Yes, the illustration was drawn by my mama, Tomari-sensei! Thank you very much!
イラストのテーマはね、ちょっとゴシック系の獅白ぼたんに仕上げていただきました。
As for the theme, she drew me in a slightly gothic style.
似合ってる！
It suits you so well!
いいでしょう。じゃ、詳細をちょっと見ていきましょう。こちら、どどん！
Pretty nice, right? Now let's look at the details. Here, boom!
はい、ステッカー！これはキービジュアルのイラストを使用した大きめサイズのステッカーです。
First, the sticker! This is a larger-sized sticker featuring the key visual illustration.
貼ってはがせるタイプになってるんで、何回でも使っていただけるかなと思ってます。
It's a peel-and-stick reusable type, so you can use it multiple times.
キラキラホログラム仕様です。かわいい！でかいね！
It has a sparkly hologram finish. Cute! And it's big!
続いてはこちら、ドン！はい、SSRBのエコバッグです！
Next up is this, boom! Yes, the SSRB Eco Bag!
ちょっとしたお買い物にね、気軽に持ち歩けるエコバッグになってます。
It's an eco bag you can easily carry around for quick shopping trips.
SSRB型のポーチも付属してるので、その中に収納していただければ持ち運びも簡単になるかなと思ってます。
It also comes with an SSRB-shaped pouch, so tucking it inside makes carrying it super easy.
買いやすい！
Very handy!
続いてはこちら！どうぞ！コンテナBOX！
Next up is this! Here you go! The Container Box!
おー！リバイバルじゃない？リバイバルだけどデザインは変わってます。
Ooh! Isn't this a revival? It's a revival, but the design has changed.
SSRBデザインのコンテナボックスになってて、折りたためる仕様になってます。
It's an SSRB-designed container box, and it can be folded flat.
これめちゃめちゃ人気だったもんね！
This one was insanely popular before!
やっぱね、みんなグッズ増えてきてると思うんで、収納していただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
Everyone's merch collection keeps growing, so I hope you use it for storage.
続いてはこちら！SSRBのティッシュカバーです！
Next up is this! The SSRB Tissue Box Cover!
かわいいーー！
So cuuute!
ふわふわ質感のSSRBモチーフのティッシュカバーになってるんで、手元に置いて鼻噛んだり涙拭いたりしてくれよな！
It's a fluffy SSRB-themed tissue cover, so keep it close by to blow your nose or wipe away tears!
そしてフルセット購入特典あります！こちら！
And there is a full set purchase bonus! Here it is!
直筆サインと箔押し複製メッセージ入りのポストカードです！
A postcard featuring a hand-written autograph and a foil-stamped printed message!
ママのイラストが最高なんで、ぜひフルセットご購入していただけたら嬉しいなと思ってます。
Mama's illustration is wonderful, so I'd be thrilled if you grab the full set!
フルだよね！これはフルセット！
Full set is the way! Definitely full set!
そして2つ目のお知らせ！こちら、はい！じゃん！
And the second announcement! Here it is, tada!
なんと獅白ぼたんの新曲『STRAY & STAY』、この後24時、9月20日日曜日の0時からデジタルリリースされます！
Shishiro Botan's brand-new song "STRAY & STAY" will be released digitally at midnight tonight, September 20th 0:00!
わーーー！パチパチパチ！
Woooow!
今回は『シミラクル』を作ってくれた椎乃味醂先生が作ってくれたんですよ、また。ありがとうございます！
This one was composed by Shiino Mirin-sensei, who also made "Simulacre"! Thank you so much!
これはなんかね、多分するめ曲だと思う。味がするんだ。ずっと味がする！
I think this song is a real "surume" track (a grower). Flavor keeps coming. It never loses flavor!
リピートしてもらえるとなんかどんどん、どんどん...
If you listen to it on repeat, more and more...
噛めば噛むほど...
The more you chew on it...
ドパドパしてくんじゃないかなと...
...the dopamine will just start rushing out...
ドパドパ！？ドパドパって何！？
Dopamine rush?! What's "dopamine rush"?!
ドパドパしてくんじゃないかなと思って。
I thought it would give you a dopamine rush.
ドパじゃないだろう！
It's not "dopa"!
はい、よろしくお願いします。
Anyway, please look forward to it!
この配信が終わった後 MV公開されますので
The MV will be released right after this stream,
ぜひお楽しみに！新曲はこの後披露しますので
so look forward to it! I'll be performing it next,
絶対に聴いてください！
so please make sure to check it out!
そして 3つ目のお知らせ まだまだあります！
And now for the 3rd announcement, there's still more!
こ、こちら！ドン！
Take a look at this! Bam!
私、獅白ぼたんの1stアルバム発売が決定しました！
My—Shishiro Botan's—1st album release has been confirmed!
おめでとうー！
Congratulations!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
記念すべき1stアルバムということで
To mark my very first album,
たっぷり10曲入ってます！
it's packed with a total of 10 tracks!
今年リリースした『シミュラクル』から『解き放て』の4曲に加え
In addition to the 4 tracks released this year, from "Simulacre" to "Tokihanate,"
生誕ライブに合わせて椎乃味醂さんに書き下ろしてもらった
the new song written by Shino Mirin for this birthday live,
新曲『Stray & Stay』ももちろん収録されてます！
"Stray & Stay," is of course included as well!
さらにさらに！
Furthermore!
まだネタバレになっちゃうから伏せたいんですけど
I'd like to keep it under wraps to avoid spoilers, but...
素敵なクリエイターの皆様に書き下ろしていただいた
five brand-new songs written by amazing creators
新曲5曲入ってます！
are included!
5曲入ってます！
Five new songs are included!
何曲！？もうわかんない！足し算できない！
How many songs in total?! I can't do addition!
獅白ぼたんの音楽を存分に感じてもらえる1枚になってるかなと
I think this is an album where you can fully experience Shishiro Botan's music,
思いますので ぜひよろしくお願いします！
so please check it out!
そして アルバムゲットしてくれた皆さんに感謝の気持ちを込めて
And as a token of my gratitude to everyone who gets the album,
全員に直筆サイン入りのグッズも用意しています！
goods with an authentic hand-signed autograph are prepared for everyone!
全員！？
For everyone?!
その他たくさん ここでしか手に入らないこだわりグッズを
In addition to that, plenty of exclusive custom items
詰め込んでますので
you can only get here are packed inside,
ぜひ詳細は公式ページをチェックしていただけたら嬉しいです！
so please check out the official website for details!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please check it out!
ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much!
このアルバムはホロライブ公式オンラインショップでこの後予約開始となります
Pre-orders for this album will start right after this on the Hololive official online shop.
頑張って作った1stアルバムなので たくさんの人に手に取ってもらえると嬉しいです！
I put my heart into making my 1st album, so I hope lots of people pick it up!
よろしくお願いしまーす！
Please check it out!
そしてですね まだあるんですよ 実は
And you know what, there's actually still more!
えー！？まだ！？
What?! Still more?!
まだあるんです／もうお腹いっぱいだよ！
There's still more! / We're already full!
ラストのこのお知らせ 結構重大発表なので
This last announcement is a pretty major one,
こちらご覧ください！ダーン！
so please take a look at this! Ta-da!
緊急告知!!
[Emergency Notice!!]
獅白ぼたん 特殊なオフイベ
Shishiro Botan: Special In-Person Event...
開催決定！
...Confirmed to be Held!
何それ！？特殊なオフイベ！？
What's that?! A "special" in-person event?!
2027年2月末から3月中旬 空けておいてね！
Please keep late February to mid-March 2027 open!
長っ！そんな長いの！？
That long?! It lasts that long?!
1日じゃないよって書いてある！
It says "Not just for one day"!
1日じゃないよ
It's not just for one day.
ということで 皆さんぜひ楽しみにしといてもらえたら嬉しいなと思ってます
So everyone, please look forward to it!
まだ詳細はね ごめんちょっと言えないんだけど
I'm sorry I can't share details just yet, but...
えー！気になる！
What?! I'm so curious!
ねぽらぼの皆さんもちょっとね 来てほしいなと思いつつ...
I'm also hoping the NePoLaBo members will come along, but...
えー！行っていいの！？
Really?! Can we go?!
まだ内緒だけどね
It's still a secret, though.
なんでよー！ちょっとネタバレしてよー！
Why?! Give us a little spoiler!
いやいや、まあなんて言ったらいいのかな...
No, no... well, how should I put it...
遊びに来てほしいかなって感じ
I'd just love for you to come have fun.
遊びに？へー！すごい楽しみ！
Come have fun? Ooh! Sounds so exciting!
まあ ちょっと楽しみにしといてください
Well, please look forward to it.
遊んでいいなら全力でふざけちゃうよ！
If we're allowed to play, we'll fool around at full power!
ふざけてほしい 期待してます
Please do. I'm counting on it.
2月末から3月中旬予定になっておりますので
It's scheduled from late February to mid-March,
情報解禁いろいろまたしていくので チェックよろしくお願いします！
so please look out for more information as it gets revealed!
以上 獅白ぼたん誕生日記念2026のグッズ情報
That concludes the Shishiro Botan Birthday Celebration 2026 merchandise info,
アルバムリリース情報、新曲情報、そして重大発表のお知らせでした！
album release info, new song info, and the major announcement!
皆さんよろしくお願いします！
Thank you everyone!
素晴らしい！
Wonderful!
じゃあみんな スタンバイ、スタンバイ
Alright everyone, time to stand by, stand by!
ここからですね いよいよライブも終盤戦ということで
From here on out, we're finally heading into the final stretch of the concert.
ねぽらぼのみんなも この後一緒に歌わせていただきますので
The NePoLaBo members will also be singing together with me in a bit,
リスナーの皆さんぜひ楽しみに待っててください！
so listeners, please look forward to it!
あとメン限アンコールライブもね！
And there's also the member-only encore live!
今日ありますので ぜひそちらも来ていただけたら嬉しいです
We have that today as well, so we'd love for you to come by!
メン限アンコールあるで！
There's a member-exclusive encore!
楽しみやー！
Can't wait!
じゃあ私 次の曲の衣装に着替えるんで みんな繋いどいてもらっていい？
I'm going to change into my outfit for the next song, so could you guys keep things going?
はーい！
Okay!
獅白の特殊なオフイベ予想しよう！
Let's try to guess what Shishiro's special in-person event is!
でもそれ当たっちゃったらどうすんの？
But what if we guess it right?
当たっちゃわない程度に大きく行こう 大きく！
Let's go big so we don't accidentally guess it right!
じゃあ「獅白ランド」開催みたいなさ
How about something like opening "Shishiro Land"?
あー！いいね！
Ah, nice!
動物園、動物園！
A zoo, a zoo!
そう！それとかどうかな？
Yeah! How about that?
特殊なオフイベ... しかも1日中じゃないからな...
A special in-person event... Plus it's not just one day...
おーい！おーい！
Hey! Hey!
逃げてー！これ以上言うとバレる可能性が！
Run! If you say any more, you might give it away!
やばいやばい！やめろやめろ！
Oh no, oh no! Stop, stop!
当たっちゃうかもしれないからね
We might actually hit the mark.
ちょっと当てられそうだったから...
You were getting dangerously close to guessing it...
着替えてきました
I'm all changed now.
ねぽらぼのみんなもちょっと準備して...
NePoLaBo members, go get ready too...
準備してきまーす！また後でね！
We'll go get ready! See you later!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
ということで ねぽらぼともこの後歌うんですが
And so, I'll be singing with NePoLaBo after this,
まずは次の曲 私の新曲をぜひ聴いてください
but first, please listen to my new song coming up next.
それでは...『Stray & Stay』
And now... "Stray & Stay."
Stray & Stay
作詞・作曲・編曲：椎乃味醂
[Stray & Stay]
[Lyrics, Composition, Arrangement: Shino Mirin]
These stars are lights
Losing the faint light,
形のない、層に沈む感覚の様、
Shapeless, like a feeling sinking through the layers,
不安定な位相が 走る思考から落ちた記憶
An unstable phase, memories falling from racing thoughts,
昨日のと同じ軌道を描く日常に、散らばった重なり合った信号。
tracing the same orbit as yesterday in daily life, overlapping scattered signals.
Stay, stay, stay in my own place.
Stray, without a trace.
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が、消えてしまう前に、
Before these jumbled words disappear,
掴みたいと
I wanted to grasp it,
願った、
I wished,
ただ繰り返した、
I just repeated it,
また繰り返して、
repeating it again,
まだ、離さないでいて。
don't let go of me just yet.
Turn me up like this
Wake up to this,
Waking from a shallow sleep,
形のない、夜に滲む知覚の様、
Shapeless, like perception blurring into the night,
未完成な鼓動、またも煌々と輝く、
An unfinished heartbeat brightly shining once more,
仮構を連ねる衝動と、同じ過去を辿る焦燥に、擦り切れる透明なもの。
a transparent essence worn down by impulses weaving fictions and impatience tracing the same past.
Sway, sway, sway out of place.
Stray, fading away.
ぐちゃぐちゃになった言葉が、色褪せる前に、
Before these jumbled words fade away,
書き留めたいと
I wanted to write it down,
思った、
I thought,
ただ繰り返した、
I just repeated it,
また繰り返して、
repeating it again,
まだ、忘れないでいて。
don't forget me just yet.
Turn me up like this
共に限界まで Burning cross brave
Together to the limit, burning cross brave!
Are you Ready? Fight!
≪ X-BRAVERS ≫
[Song: X-BRAVERS]
Lala... Rurila...
何度地べたに這いずり 土を噛んだって
No matter how many times we crawled in the dirt and bit the dust,
防ぎ合い背を任す 戦場に咲く友がいる
We guard and watch each other's backs—friends blooming on the battlefield.
ガチンコ(本気)でシャバ(危険)なときも 何故か立ち向かえる
Even in serious and dangerous moments, somehow we can face them head-on.
スフォルツァンドの臨界値まで フォルテの銀河に溺れよう
Up to the critical limit of sforzando, let's drown in a galaxy of forte!
Buru-buru-buru-buru-buru-buru
ブルったって突き出せる
Even if we tremble, we can break through!
Buru-buru-buru-buru-buru-buru
タフとしても振り絞れ
Even if it's tough, muster every bit of strength!
人が創る想いの 答えを信じよう
Let's believe in the answer to the feelings that people create!
ハートを震わせて 愛で殴れ
Make your heart tremble, strike with love!
100度負けても101度目に勝てる
Even if we lose 100 times, we can win on the 101st!
この力とは？ この絆とは？
What is this power? What is this bond?
みんなが紡いだ 歌と響きだ
It's the song and resonance that everyone spun!
交わる勇気 託し合って
Entrusting to each other the intersecting courage,
Never give up!
さあ夜明けへと
Now, onward to the dawn!
怖さ 弱さ 涙は 千切って分け合い
Tear apart and share our fear, weakness, and tears,
勝利を掴め！
and seize victory!
握れば握るほどまた 開く意味を知り
The more I clench my fists, the more I know the meaning of opening them,
相手の悲痛が伝わり 無刀の極みへ焦がれる
Feeling the opponent's grief, I yearn for the height of the swordless way.
因縁の連鎖にこそ 撃鉄を起こせ…カッ！
Cock the hammer in the very chain of fate... fire!
鎮魂歌(レクイエム)じゃなく 奏で合っ...
Rather than a requiem, we played together...
Error processing subtitles for this segment.